<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prepare the Environment on AWS System Manager</title><link>/2-prepare-environment/</link><description>Recent content in Prepare the Environment on AWS System Manager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/2-prepare-environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy using CloudFormation</title><link>/2-prepare-environment/2.1-deploy-cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2-prepare-environment/2.1-deploy-cloudformation/</guid><description>This guide provides step-by-step instructions for deploying the complete Security Automation platform using the AWS Management Console and a CloudFormation template.
Prerequisites Before you begin, you will need:
An AWS Account with administrative permissions. The final IaC.yaml CloudFormation template file for this project, downloaded to your local machine. Step 1: Navigate to CloudFormation In the AWS Management Console, type &amp;ldquo;CloudFormation&amp;rdquo; into the search bar and select it. Ensure you are in your desired AWS Region.</description></item><item><title>Configuring the Serverless Aplication</title><link>/2-prepare-environment/2.2-configuring-application/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2-prepare-environment/2.2-configuring-application/</guid><description>After your CloudFormation stack has been successfully created, there are a few essential configuration steps you must complete manually to make the platform fully operational.
1. Adding Code to Your Lambda Functions The CloudFormation template deployed all seven of your Lambda functions with simple placeholder code. You now need to upload the actual application and security logic for each one.
Prepare Your Code: For each of your seven Lambda functions, visit the following link to download the lambda code and see additional instructions for configuration https://github.</description></item></channel></rss>